<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zazu App</title>
    <description>Zazu is a new open source productivity app, that allows developers to be in the drivers seat. Unlike other solutions, there are no built in integrations, so every plugin has the full scope of what Zazu has to offer.
</description>
    <link>http://zazuapp.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://zazuapp.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 10:59:49 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 10:59:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zazu&#39;s v0.5.0 is released!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;bugs&quot;&gt;Bugs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few bugs that were fixed. For example if you ever tried
narrowing down your plugin logs in the debugger, it wasn’t working as correctly,
but it’s fixed now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; more resilient, yet again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are introducing a new block type &lt;a href=&quot;http://zazuapp.org/documentation/blocks/#preview&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to
display large text on the screen, compared to a small notification. This would
be useful for presentations, or for more accessible communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fixed quite a few more bugs and added a few more features, be sure to check
out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tinytacoteam/zazu/blob/master/changelog.md#050&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; for information on the rest of the bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://zazuapp.org/blog/2017/video-introduction-to-zazu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zazuapp.org/blog/2017/video-introduction-to-zazu</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video Introduction to Zazu</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/206729309&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a short video about Zazu. Zazu is an open source launcher on steroids.
It ships with a rich set of plugins to make your life easy. You can write your
own plugins to extend the behavior of Zazu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-zazu&quot;&gt;Install Zazu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Zazu please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/&quot;&gt;website and download&lt;/a&gt; the
appropriate binary for your operating system. Zazu is cross-platform compatible
and we currently supply binaries for Windows, Mac and Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-zazu&quot;&gt;Using Zazu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it is successfully installed, you can launch Zazu. You’ll notice the
feather icon in the menu bar of your operating system. You can now open Zazu
using the shortcut key &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Alt-Space&lt;/code&gt;. Launching an application is as simple as
typing a few letters from the name of the program. For example typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chr&lt;/code&gt;
will show &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/code&gt; in the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;default-plugins&quot;&gt;Default Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zazu ships with a rich set of plugins that go beyond the simple application
launching. One such plugin is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/tinytacoteam/zazu-calculator&quot;&gt;calculator&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to do
math calculations such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;5 * 3&lt;/code&gt;. You can then press enter to automatically
copy that result into the clipboard. It can also do a few advanced calculations
like converting between feet to inches or pounds to kilograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful plugin that ships by default is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tinytacoteam/zazu-clipboard&quot;&gt;clipboard
manager&lt;/a&gt; which can be launched using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cmd-Shift-V&lt;/code&gt;. You can search
through this list of items you’ve copied earlier in the day. It can also show
you a handy preview of the images you have copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-plugins&quot;&gt;Installing Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real power of Zazu lies with the plugins contributed by users to satisfy
their specific needs. You can browse through a list of available plugins on the
[plugins page][plugins page] or you can look at them straight from Zazu by
typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;list&lt;/code&gt;. To install plugins you can type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;install emoji&lt;/code&gt; and click on the
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emoji&lt;/code&gt; plugin you’d like to install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updating-your-configuration&quot;&gt;Updating your Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration for Zazu is stored in a simple JSON file in your home folder.
In MacOS and Linux you can find this file under &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/.zazurc.json&lt;/code&gt;. On Windows you
can find it in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C:\Users\YOUR_NAME\.zazurc.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your configuration file, you have options to modify the hotkey to launch
Zazu, change the theme, or modify the configuration for individual plugins. Like
the fallback searches to show in the results list, or the hotkey for the
clipboard manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is a text file, you can also back it up, version it and share it with
others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-plugins&quot;&gt;Creating Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in creating plugins for Zazu you can find lots of help in
the &lt;a href=&quot;/documentation/&quot;&gt;documentation of the website&lt;/a&gt;, you can also reach out to the
core team or the community members on &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitter.im/tinytacoteam/zazu&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;. Lastly, if you run into
bugs please file an issue on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tinytacoteam/zazu&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://zazuapp.org/blog/2017/video-introduction-to-zazu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zazuapp.org/blog/2017/video-introduction-to-zazu</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
